A Guide to the Shelton-Winn-Oliver Family Papers, 1764-1872
Library of Virginia
- Shelton-Winn-Oliver Family Papers, 1779-1864, 1872 (Folder 1-10)
  - Papers, 1860-1872 (Folder 10)
    - Letter, 29 May 1864, from Lt. Colonel Francis A. Walker, A.A.G. for Major General Winfield Scott Hancock to Mrs. Colonel Edwin Shelton informing her that her farm will be a site for placement of artillery and offering to remove her and her family to a safer location. Reply of the same date from Mrs. Shelton states that her daughter is very ill and cannot be moved. Reply is addressed to General Hancock., 2 leaves, negative photostats
    - Letter, 30 May 1864, from Lt. Colonel Francis A. Walker, A.A.G. for Major General Winfield Scott Hancock to Mrs. Colonel Edwin Shelton reiterating that her farm will be a site for the placement of artillery and again offering to remover her family to a safer location. Reply of the same date from Mrs. Shelton again states that her daughter is too ill to be moved., 3 leaves, negative photostats
    - Letter, 19 July 1864, from Brigadier General W. C. Wickham to Colonel Edwin Shelton concerning forage., 2 pages, negative photostats
    - Chancery suit, 26 July 1864, 25 October 1864, 22 November 1864, in Hanover County Court, Nancy Cross v. Jordan Harris and Margaret E., his wife; Walter T. Gilman and Betty Ann, his wife; Henry G. Cross; Eldridge Cross in his own right and as trustee for Cora E. and Jane S. McDowell; Joseph F. Cross; Thomas Ellett and Mary S., his wife; and Cora E. and Jane S. McDowell the two last of whom are infants under the age of twenty-one years by Robert O. Doswell, their guardian., 9 pages
    - Election poll, 18 August 1864, from the Negrofoot precinct for a magistrate for the county of Hanover., 7 leaves, negative photostats
    - Plat, 2 August 1872, of 189 acres in Hanover County, being the estate of Williamson Talley., 1 leaf
- Estate Papers of Henry King, 1819-1846 (Folder 11-19)
  - Will, 22 April 1822 (Folder 11)
  - Letters, 1825-1845 (Folder 12)
  - Legal Papers, 1819-1845 (Folder 13)
  - Promissory Notes and Miscellany 1830-1837 (Folder 14)
  - Accounts, 1820-1845 (Folder 15)
  - Receipts, 1822-1837 (Folder 16)
  - Receipts, 1838-1839 (Folder 17)
  - Receipts, 1843-1846 (Folder 18)
- Shelton-Winn-Oliver Family Papers, (Accession 24827), 1764, 1815-1860 (Folder 19)
  - Papers, 1764, 1815-1860, 86 leaves, negative photostats (Folder 19)
    - Deed, 15 October 1764, for 550 acres in Hanover County on which the court house is situated from John Shelton and Eleanor, his wife, of Hanover County; Eleanor Parks of Hanover County, widow of William Parks, late of the City of Williamsburg; to Paul Tilman of Hanover County. Recorded in Hanover County 6 December 1764., 4 leaves, negative photostats
    - Will, 17 October 1815, of Walter Coles of Hanover County. Codicil, 9 November 1815. Will proved in Hanover County 27 December 1815., 4 pages, negative photostats
    - Estate accounts, 1825-1831, of Mosby Sheppard of Hanover County., 8 leaves, negative photostats
    - Estate accounts, 1831-1832, of Peter Winston of Hanover County., 15 leaves, negative photostats
    - Bond, 29 May 1833, of Henry Clay of Ashland and James Erwin of the Woodlands, in Kentucky, to Edwin Shelton of Hanover County, administrator of Peter Foster. Concerns money bequeathed by Peter Foster to Henry Clay's wife. No recordation shown., 4 leaves, negative photostats
    - Estate accounts, 18 December 1849, of sales of the effects of Jesse Winn, deceased, made by William R. Winn, his executor., 20 leaves, negative photostats
    - Estate accounts, 1850-1854, of the estate of Parke Street in account with Charles P. Goodall, his executor., 11 leaves, negative photostats
    - Commissioner's report, 26 August 1856, of sale of land in suit of John Thacker vs. Jesse Thacker and others, Hanover County, W. R. Winn, commissioner., 3 leaves, negative photostats
    - Commissioner's report, 28 October 1856, of sale of land in suit of Jonas P. Woodson and others vs. Frederick A. Woodson and others, Hanover County, W. R. Winn, commissioner., 2 leaves, negative photostats
    - Bill of injunction, 17 July 1860, Robert Ellett vs. Commissioners, etc. concerns the involved matter of the purchase of Darracott's Mill by Robert Ellett., 14 leaves, negative photostats
    - Photograph, n.d., of a drawing of "Studley" in Hanover County., 1 leaf, negative photostat